morningconsult.com 2015-03-14

# Privacy Policy - Morning Consult

**PRIVACY POLICY**

**Last Updated:**  September 14, 2014

This Privacy Policy discloses the privacy practices for the www.TheMorningConsult.com website and all mobile websites and applications associated therewith (“MC Media”), which is provided by The Morning Consult, LLC (“Morning Consult”). This Privacy Policy governs Morning Consult’s collection of information from you through your use of MC Media. It does not apply to any information you may provide to Morning Consult through other means, e.g., via mail or via telephone. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully so that you understand Morning Consult’s online privacy practices. By using MC Media, you agree that your visit, download or use of MC Media, and any dispute over Morning Consult’s online privacy practices, is governed by this Privacy Policy and Morning Consult’s [Terms and Condition of Use](http://morningconsult.com/terms-and-conditions-of-use/). Questions regarding privacy issues should be directed to [Michael@morningconsult.com](mailto:Michael@morningconsult.com) or Morning Consult, P.O. Box 15628, Washington, DC 20003.

**TYPES OF INFORMATION MORNING CONSULT COLLECTS**

Morning Consult collects: (1) information voluntarily supplied through optional subscriptions; and (2) information regarding users’ navigation through MC Media.

Morning Consult may collect and store information, personal or otherwise, that you voluntarily supply either while navigating MC Media or when corresponding via email with Morning Consult. Some examples of this type of information include personal information (such as your name, title, organizational affiliation, and email address) that you provide when you subscribe for MC Media. The information supplied will help Morning Consult provide the service requested, offer you more personalized features, and tailor MC Media and advertisements to your perceived interests. Supplying such information is entirely voluntary. However, if you choose NOT to supply the requested information, Morning Consult may be unable to provide you with services made available to other users of MC Media.

Morning Consult also may collect and store information that is generated automatically as you navigate through MC Media. For example, to help make MC Media more responsive to the needs of users, Morning Consult employs a standard feature of browser software, called a “cookie,” to assign each user a unique, random number that resides on a user’s computer. The cookie does not personally identify the user; it merely identifies the computer with which the user accesses MC Media. Unless a user voluntarily identifies himself or herself (through subscription, for example), MC Media will not be able to identify the identity of the user, even if a cookie is assigned to a user’s computer. The personal information a cookie can contain is information supplied by a user. Morning Consult may also track device identification statistics and other non-identifying information for the purpose of analytics, push notifications, and error reporting. Analytics may be provided to third party vendors. By showing how and when visitors use MC Media, cookies help Morning Consult’s track user trends and patterns. They also prevent you from having to re-enter your preferences on certain areas of MC Media where you have entered preference information before. Of course, you are free to set your web browser not to accept cookies; however, doing so may render your computer unable to take advantage of the personalized features enjoyed by other users of MC Media.

Morning Consult also may use web beacons (also known as “single-pixel GIFs”) to access cookies and to count users who visit MC Media or open Morning Consult’s HTML-formatted email messages. MC Media’s servers automatically collect limited information about your computer’s connection to the Internet, including your IP address. The IP address is a number that lets computers attached to the Internet know where to send data – such as the web pages users view. An IP address does not personally identify a user. Morning Consult uses this information to deliver MC Media’s content to you upon request and to measure traffic within MC Media.

Morning Consult may use cookies, web beacons and similar technologies, and a third party ad serving software, to collect information about users of MC Media and about activity that occurs within MC Media, and Morning Consult may use this information to, among other things, serve targeted advertisements on MC Media, and possibly on other websites, tailored to match your perceived interests. The information collected allows Morning Consult to analyze how users use MC Media and to track user interests, trends, and patterns. Morning Consult also may use third party advertising companies to target and serve some of the advertisements that appear on MC Media, and these companies likewise may use their own cookies, web beacons, and similar technologies to collect information from users of MC Media. The information collected by these companies may include the IP address of your computer. These companies may use that information, sometimes in conjunction with similar information gathered from other websites, to deliver advertisements on MC Media, and possibly on other websites (if the third party advertising company operates an advertising network), tailored to match the perceived interests of consumers. Morning Consult authorizes the collection of personal information by third party advertisers through advertising technologies deployed in ads that may appear on Morning Consult without separate consent. The collection and use of information by these companies is governed by the relevant third party’s privacy policy and is not covered by Morning Consult’s privacy policy.

Morning Consult takes privacy and security very seriously, and strive to put our members first in all aspects of our business. With regard to Do Not Track (“DNT”) signals, Morning Consult currently does not respond to DNT signals in browsers.

We may collect information about you from other sources, including through interactive applications (such as mobile devices, third-party services, and embedded audio and video players), from co-branded partners, and from commercially available sources (such as data aggregators and public databases).

Please note that all of the information we collect about you may be combined, including to help us tailor our communications to you and to develop rich online content and services.

**USE AND DISCLOSURE OF INFORMATION**

Morning Consult uses the information it collects from you in a variety of ways, including using the information to customize features and advertising that appear on MC Media. Morning Consult also may provide your information to third parties, such as service providers, contractors, and advertisers, for a variety of purposes. For example, Morning Consult may provide Morning Consult’s advertisers with information about you and other visitors that will enable Morning Consult’s advertisers to better target ads to specific types of visitors.

You agree that Morning Consult may use your information to contact you for customer service purposes, to inform you of important changes and additions to MC Media or the services offered over MC Media, and to send you administrative notices, offers, requests for feedback, and any other communications that Morning Consult believes may be of interest to you.

Morning Consult reserves the right to disclose to third parties all of the information that Morning Consult collects online about you and other visitors.

Please be aware that Morning Consult may occasionally release information about visitors when release is appropriate to comply with law, to enforce Morning Consult’s [Terms and Condition of Use](http://morningconsult.com/terms-and-conditions-of-use/), or to protect the rights, property or safety of visitors to MC Media, the public, or to Morning Consult.

Please also note that as Morning Consult’s business grows, Morning Consult may buy or sell various assets. In the unlikely event that Morning Consult, some or all of Morning Consult’s assets, or MC Media is acquired by another company, information about Morning Consult’s visitors may be among the transferred assets.

**THIRD PARTY SITES**

MC Media includes links to third party websites whose privacy policies Morning Consult do not control. Once you leave MC Media, any information you provide at another site will be governed by the privacy policy of the operator of MC Media you are visiting. The privacy policies of third party websites will likely differ from ours.

Please note that Morning Consult provides you MC Media at no cost. If you make a purchase through a third party site, the privacy policy of the third party site will govern your credit card number or other financial information.

**CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

This children’s privacy statement explains Morning Consult’s practices with respect to the online collection and use of personal information from children under the age of thirteen, and provides important information on your and parental rights under federal law with respect to such information.

MC Media is not directed to children under the age of thirteen and Morning Consult does NOT knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen. Morning Consult requires subscribers’ occupational information to dissuade users under the age of thirteen from subscribing. If Morning Consult becomes aware that Morning Consult has inadvertently received personally-identifiable information from a user under the age of thirteen, Morning Consult will delete such information from Morning Consult’s records. Because Morning Consult does not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of thirteen, Morning Consult also does NOT knowingly distribute any such information to third parties. Morning Consult does NOT knowingly allow children under the age of thirteen to distribute personally identifiable contact information.

**MODIFYING YOUR INFORMATION AND OPTING OUT**

If you subscribe with Morning Consult, you will have the opportunity opt-out of receiving future MC Media. If you have received an email from Morning Consult, you will have the opportunity to unsubscribe from future emails by using the “Unsubscribe” link at the bottom of the email, at any time. Upon using the “Unsubscribe” link, if you choose to “Remove yourself from all The Morning Consult email lists” you will no longer receive Morning Consult’s daily email briefings and other updates. You may also manage and modify some of your subscription and personal information, through the “Manage Your Subscription” link at the bottom of each email sent by Morning Consult, at any time.

**STORAGE OF INFORMATION**

All information gathered by Morning Consult is stored within a database accessible only to us. However, despite Morning Consult’s best use of reasonable security measures, no security system is impenetrable. Morning Consult cannot guarantee the security of Morning Consult’s database, nor can Morning Consult guarantee that information supplied will not be intercepted while being transmitted over the Internet (e.g., the NSA may be watching).

**CHANGES TO THIS POLICY**

The Internet is an evolving medium and this Privacy Policy is subject to change without notice. In the event that Morning Consult does update this Privacy Policy, the modified Privacy Policy will be accessible on MC Media and the Effective Date of the Privacy Policy will be updated to reflect the date of the changes. By continuing to use MC Media after Morning Consult post any such changes, you accept the Privacy Policy as modified.
